Guide to the Kenya rural development project reports, 1974-1991.
Kenya rural development project reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kenya rural development project reports, 1974-1991.
4336
Kenya. Ministry of Planning and National Development.
5.2 cubic ft.
Plans and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
District development plans for specific districts in Kenya; reports from various individuals on planning topics.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
District development plans for specific districts in Kenya, 1974-1978, 1979-1983, and 1984-1988; project reports, 1986-1991; reports from various individuals on planning topics including training, information systems, employment, food shortages, rural-urban policy and development, demography, arid and semi-arid land development, and financial aspects; and project reports. Participants included Ward Henevelt, John M. Cohen, Richard M. Hook, F.D. Van Buer, A.U. Wandera, Emery Roe, Marcia L. Odell, Alan G. Johnston, Klaus Bethke, Clay G. Westcott, Sid Saltzman, Judith Geist, David B. Lewis, Hugh E. Evans, George Ruigu, Barclay G. Jones, Peter Weisel, R.W. Machina, John Carlsen, and John T. Saywell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kenya.; Bethke, Klaus W.; Carlsen, John, 1944-; Cohen, John M.; Evans, Hugh Emrys.; Geist, Judith Karen.; Henevelt, Ward.; Hook, Richard M.; Johnston, Alan G.; Jones, Barclay G. (Barclay Gibbs); Lewis, David B. (David Burton); Machina, R. W.; Odell, Marcia Larson, 1945-; Roe, Emery.; Ruigu, George.; Saltzman, Sidney.; Saywell, John T., 1929-2011.; Van Buer, F. D.; Wandera, A. U.; Weisel, Peter Fowler, 1939-; Westcott, Clay G.
Subjects:
Rural development -- Kenya.; Rural development -- International cooperation.; Rural development -- Social aspects -- Kenya.; Rural development projects -- Kenya.; Rural development; Rural development projects
Places:
Kenya
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- District Development Plans
  - District Development Plans - Baringo, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Bungoma, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Busia, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Elgeyo-Marakwet, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Embu, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Garissa, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Isiolo, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kajiado, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kakamega, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kericho, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kiambu, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kilifif, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kirinyaga, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kitui, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kwale, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Laikipia, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Lamu, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Machakos, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mandera, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Marsabit, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Meru, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mombasa, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Murang's, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nakuru, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nandi, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nyandarua, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nyeri, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Samburu, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Siaya, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - South Nyanza, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Tana River, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Trans Nzoia, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Turkana, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Uasin Gishu, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Wajir, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - West Pokot, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kisii, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kisumu, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Laikipia, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Lamu, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mandera, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Marsabit, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Meru, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mombasa, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Muranga, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nakuru, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Samburu, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Siaya, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - South Nyanza, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Taita Taveta, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Tana River, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Trans Nzoia, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Turkana, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Uasin Gishu, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Wajir, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - West Pokot, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Baringo, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Bungoma, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Busia, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Elgeyo-Marakwet, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Embu, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Isiolo, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kajiado, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kakamega, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kericho, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kiambu, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kilifi, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kirinyaga, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kisii, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kisumu, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kitui, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Kwale, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Lamu, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Machakos, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mandera, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Marsabit, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Meru, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Mombasa, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Murang'a, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nakuru, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nandi, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Marok, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nyandarua, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Nyeri, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Samburu, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Siaya (2), 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - South Nyanza, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Taita-Taveta, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Tana River, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Trans Nzoia, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Turkana, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Uasin Gishu, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - Wajir, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - District Development Plans - West Pokot, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Related Materials
  - Monitoring of District Level Development Activities in Kenya, 1981-09; Henevelt, Ward; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - District Development Planning in Kenya, 1985-10-1986-01; Cohen, John M.; Hook, Robert M.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Increasing Role of District in the Planning and Budgeting Process, 1983-04; Van Buer, F. D.; Wandera, A. U.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - District Focus and the Problem of Project Implementation, 1984-06-06; Roe, Emery; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Improving Rural Planning in Kenya: Training Activities for the Rural Planning Project, 1982-08-28; Odell, Marcia L.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Report for the Rural Planning Project
  - Training for Implementation of the District Focus for Rural Development, 1983-05; Johnston, Alan G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Training for Implementation of the District Focus for Rural Development, 1983-05-10; Johnston, Alan G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Executive Summary
  - Small Projects for Rural Development: Selection and Formulation Guidelines, 1983-12; Gethke, Klaus; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Monitoring of District-Level Development, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Microprocessors and Financial Management for District Focus in Kenya, 1983-03; Wescott, Clay G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Design of Infrastructure Inventory and Project Monitoring Information Systems for Rural Development, 1984-02; Saltzman, Sid; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 12)
    A Report Prepared for the Rural Planning Division in the Ministry of Finance and Planning of the Government of Kenya
  - Rural Infrastructure Inventory Information System (RIIIS): Continuation of the Design Process, 1985-02-1985-11; Saltzman, Sid; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Microcomputers for Improved Budgeting by the Kenya Government, 1985-11; Wescott, Clay G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Harambee Resource Mobilization and Basic Needs, 1984-05-05; Geist, Judith; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Background Paper for the National Seminar on Employment and Basic Needs Planning in Kenya, 6 - 12 May, 1984
  - District Focus and Population Planning, 1984-11-28; Johnston, Alan G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Role of Government in Combatting Food Shortages: Lessons from Kenya 1984-85, 1985-06; Cohen, John M.; Lewis, David B. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rural-Urban Policy Analysis and Coordination: Issues, Tasks and Staffing, 1984-11; Evans, Hugh; Rural-urban Policy Analysis Unit (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Approaches to Rural-Urban Development: A Discussion Paper, 1985-05-22; Evans, Hugh; Rural-urban Policy Analysis Unit (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Paper prepared for the workshop entitled "Approaches to Rural-Urban Development," Institute for Development Studies, University of Nairobi
  - Approaches to Rural-Urban Development: Proceedings for a Workshop Organized by the Institute for Development Studies, University of Nairobi, 1985-05-22 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Evans, Hugh, Ruigu, George; Rural Planning Department
  - Observations on the Rural-Urban Balance in Kenya, 1985-06-01; Jones, Barclay G.; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Rural-Urban Policy Analysis Unit, Ministry of Finance and Planning
  - District Demographic Profiles from the 1984-1988 District Development Plans, 1984-04; Rural Planning Division (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - District Focus for Rural Development, 1984-07-01; Office of the President (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Development Coordination and Cabinet Office
  - Summary Report: Ministry Implementation Plans for the District Focus for Rural Developmen, 1986-03; Office of the President (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - National Training Strategy for District Focus, 1985-03; Office of the President (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Arid and Semi Arid Lands Development in Kenya: The Framework for Implementation, Programme Planning, and Evaluation, 1979-05; Government of Kenya, Ministry of Agriculture (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Compendium on Development Co-operation with Knyaas of 30th June, 1984, 1985; Ministry of Finance and Planning (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Kenya District Microcomputer Experiment: Second Report, 1985-06-1985-08; Rural Planning Department (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Kenya District Microcomputer Experiment: Second Report, 1985-09-1985-12; Rural Planning Department (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Economic Survey 1985: Chapter 3: Urban Housing and Development, 1985; Central Bureau of Statistics (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - A Manual for Rural Planning, 1974-06; Institute for Development Studies (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Some Issues Related to District Development, 1977-03; Weisel, Peter; Rural Planning Unit (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Discussion Paper No. 1
  - District Planning: Proposals for Local Level Planning and Management, 1977-03; Machina, R. W. Weisel, Peter; Rural Planning Unit (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Discussion Paper No. 2
  - Monitoring and Evaluating Rural Development Programmes: With Specific Reference to the Integrated Agricultural Development Programme, 1977-03 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Weisel, Peter, Rural Planning Unit
    Discussion Paper No. 3
  - The Rural Development Fund: 3 Years' Experiences and Some Thoughts Regarding the Future Development, 1985-12; Carlsen, John (Box 4, Folder 1)
    RDF Discussion Paper
  - Rural Planning Project: Kenya: Project Paper (615-0162, 1976-04-28; Agency for International Development (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Rural Planning Project, Rural Planning Section, Ministry of Economic Planning and Community Affairs: A Mid-term Evaluation, 1979-03; Saywell, John T. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rural Planning Project, Rural Planning Division, Ministry of Economic Planning and Development: Response to Mid-term Evaluation, 1980-03 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rural Planning Division
  - Kenya: Rural Planning II Project: Project Paper 615-0189, 1980-08; Agency for International Development (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kenya Rural Planning Project: Phase II, 1981-02-23 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Rural Planning Project Phase II: Mid-Term Evaluation for USAID, 1983-09-1983-10; Saywell, John T. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rural Planning Project Progress Report, 1983-01-1983-08 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - District Focus for Rural Development, 1987-03; Office of President (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Finance Corporation, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Finance Corporation, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Finance Corporation, 1963-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Finance Corporation - Statistical Digest Vol. No. 1, 1988-03 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Resource Management for Rural Development Project: Semi-Annual Report No. 7, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Resource Management for Rural Development Project: Semi-Annual Report No. 8, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Statistical Abstract, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fiscal Role of Local Government in Developing Countries: Lessons from Kenya, 1988-05; Smoke, Paul Joseph (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Ph.D. thesis